<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-08-25T20:07:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Aspr</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/25/ASPR.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aspr" /><published>2024-08-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-08-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/25/ASPR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/25/ASPR.html"><![CDATA[<p>“All models are wrong, but some are useful.” - every statistics textbook, but most relevantly to me, Modeling Social Behavior by Smaldino.</p>

<p>This post is super late and thus will be super brief, but in February I went to ASPR, a camp similar to SPARC, but held in rural Taiwan rather than UC Berkeley. I went to SPARC back in 2022 during the summer, and was excited for ASPR.</p>

<p>My flight was first from BOS to SFO, then from SFO to TPE in Taiwan. The whole trip was a little over 20 hours. The food was delicious and I completed all my schoolwork for the week (ASPR was held during winter break but still overlapped with a few days of school).</p>

<p>I had met another person from Boston going to ASPR in BOS (and they were who I was assigned to introduce during third-party introductions, a twist on typical introductions) and we met another person at SFO. A third person was also going to ASPR but we didn’t see them on the plane. Once we landed at TPE, we met up with a larger group of students headed to ASPR. An instructor was there to drive us to the camp, which was held on a sheep farm in the mountains, and, as I learned later, the last (and only) location permitted to be built on those mountains as a touristy spot. The ride was 2-3 hours and filled with so many twists and turns that I felt sick by the end of it. At camp I met everyone, fed sheep, and picked up Modeling Social Behavior from the book pile. Jetlagged, I fell asleep at 9 and awoke promptly the next morning at 5.</p>

<p>I spent my time walking around the balcony and exploring the place. It was truly beautiful, from the sunrise and sunshine to the nature that surrounded us. It felt like paradise.</p>

<p>I had a few more one on ones the next day, herded the sheep, said hi to the local puppy, and felted wool I sheared from the sheep. One instructor tried to teach me to do handstands, and I hiked through the forest in the mornings. I cut bamboo for the first time, led the grill at a BBQ, danced, sang karaoke, and then went on a midnight surprise adventure where we only returned at 3. I visited TSMC’s museum, a mall, Daxi bridge, ate street food, ran a game theory game, then had hot pot and boba for dinner. I fed the sheep from my hand and tried new fruit that made me feel fuzzy. I raced to Taipei 101 with friends, and walked along the road, ducking when cars came near (we yelled “Car!”). I learned why “black sheep” is a phrase - people did avoid the singular black sheep in the flock, LOL. I read books and enjoyed nature and had fun.</p>

<p>On the flight back, I tried beef noodle soup (a staple of Taiwan) at the airport, and it was soo good. I took home a couple of books, as well as some pokemon plushies and an IKEA golden retriever plushy. Our flight from SFO to BOS was cancelled, so we flew to NJ where we overnighted at the airport (no hotel because none of us were over 21). I felt exhausted but happy when I finally returned home.</p>

<p>I met so many new friends and I truly think ASPR was an amazing experience that changed who I am as a person.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“All models are wrong, but some are useful.” - every statistics textbook, but most relevantly to me, Modeling Social Behavior by Smaldino.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hacknight</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/22/Hacknight.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hacknight" /><published>2024-08-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/22/Hacknight</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/22/Hacknight.html"><![CDATA[<p>This is super late, but I want to talk a bit about Hacknight, a hackathon at BB&amp;N. It was my first hackathon that I won, and though I’m a bit biased since I won, it’s been my favorite hackathon yet!</p>

<p>I had been to larger hackathons like Blueprint before, so seeing a contest run by a high school was pretty wholesome, in the way that smaller clubs are more wholesome than big ones, since you see the hiccups and imperfections along the way. One example is the awards ceremony, where instead of having this polished rehearsed ceremony where there’s a stage and people are secretly told beforehand and do demos, it was a slideshow and a quick receiving of awards. Or the pin maker, where we were directed to a different room to make pins at Angelhacks, here we weren’t really told about it except in quick passing and we had access throughout.</p>

<p>I arrived a day early to join in on the learnathon. My club members weren’t coming until later, so during lunch when I saw two people asking a third person if they wanted to join their group, I asked if they needed a fourth. Thus the team was formed. They announced the hackathon theme was “sidequest”, so we started brainstorming over dinner. The food at the hackathon was amazing, by the way.</p>

<p>We found a room for ourselves, and came up with the idea of a google extension. One of the members had experience with making google extensions, and they said it was super simple, just like a webpage but with a manifest.json file. Our idea was that the google extension would alert you every few minutes to take a break by playing a minigame (a “sidequest”). We headed out to go to a workshop for making a website where they were giving out free boba!</p>

<p>I headed to bed around 12, and woke up early the next day for breakfast. I saw that my club members were here and greeted them, then I returned to my team. The rest of the day went pretty smooth. We made different minigames, a logo, and a default container webpage with a points system. We named it SideQuest.</p>

<p>Then it was time for judging. The way it worked is we first a peer judging system, then the organizers would judge the submissions. We took turns presenting and checking out other teams, where we voted for them using candy!</p>

<p>Before the awards ceremony, we cleaned up our room and one of my teammates, who was a student at BB&amp;N, gave us a tour. Then we returned and learned that we won first place overall, both in judging and by having the most candy votes! We were really happy and high-fived each other before going to the front to claim our prize (Raspberry Pis). We took our candy cup and also more candy from a giant bag. The candy was sweet.</p>

<p>Finally, we went out for pictures, then everyone began to leave. We exchanged contact info, and the hackathon was over.</p>

<p>You can download our app from the Chrome Web Store <a href="https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/sidequest/lndafcnkmnkbjdoijfnceebpaejmhhdp">here</a>.
You can check out our code <a href="https://github.com/swan-07/sidequest/tree/main">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>stephanie</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is super late, but I want to talk a bit about Hacknight, a hackathon at BB&amp;N. It was my first hackathon that I won, and though I’m a bit biased since I won, it’s been my favorite hackathon yet!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lexington Sprouts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/22/Lexington-Sprouts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lexington Sprouts" /><published>2024-08-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/22/Lexington-Sprouts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/22/Lexington-Sprouts.html"><![CDATA[<p>Another summer, another year of LexSprouts. Oh, I really should say AlltheSprouts now, since we’re no longer just in Lexington. Hopkinton opened their branch recently.</p>

<p>Science Outdoors went smoothly, as usual. We opened up registration, received a bunch of responses, then went through all of them to narrow down our list to 10-15 students. We booked a room in the Community Center and prepared lesson plans. With 5 teachers to switch between, no one felt overwhelmed and we got to teach everything that we felt was fun (science mainly, hence the course name, but I also got a lockpicking lecture in there too!)</p>

<p>The last day went great. The students loved the competition, and we also ordered pizza and candy.</p>

<p>Slice of Art went well, also! I taught a few classes to the kids, starting with still life (an apple), the human figure, then portrait.</p>]]></content><author><name>stephanie</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another summer, another year of LexSprouts. Oh, I really should say AlltheSprouts now, since we’re no longer just in Lexington. Hopkinton opened their branch recently.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beaver Works Summer Institute</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/06/Beaver-Works-Summer-Institute.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beaver Works Summer Institute" /><published>2024-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-08-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/06/Beaver-Works-Summer-Institute</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/06/Beaver-Works-Summer-Institute.html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last month, I attended Beaver Works Summer Institute (BWSI). BWSI is a summer engineering program for high schoolers, with both online and in-person options and a variety of different course options, from unmanned aerial vehicles to e-textiles. I took the Embedded Security and Hardware Hacking course, a class in-person at MIT over the span of a month. It was absolutely amazing.</p>

<p>Class took place every day from 10 am - 5 pm, but since I live around 40 minutes away by bus (and the Red Line decided to break down right as the course began until halfway through), I was waking up at 7:30 - 8:30 am every day. Sometimes when I’d miss the bus, I’d get creative. I went on a nature walk once trying to find a different bus station. I biked to Alewife multiple times, trying out different routes. When the Red Line was down, I sometimes walked 40 minutes from Harvard to MIT, other times I took the express and non-express shuttle buses. I listened to audiobooks, finishing “Cat’s Cradle” by Vonnegut, “Ghost in the Wires” by Mitnick, and “The Phantom Tollbooth” by Juster. It was fun, a time of exploration.</p>

<p>We would have lectures and labs in class. We had a pot of grass that people could touch, and a pot of marbles as a counter for when an instructor said “chat”. We had guest lecturers on cryptography and side channel attacks, from DPA to Spectre and Meltdown. All the instructors were really cool, and a learned a lot about computers, C, hacking, and reverse engineering.</p>

<p>About a week in, we split into groups and were given tiva boards for our final project, coding a bootloader and a protocol for securely transmitting firmware onto it. I made lots of friends, and during lunch I’d try to find instructors to sit outside with us (the sunlight felt nice).</p>

<p>Speaking of lunches, they were great. Each week we had lunch from a different catering service, though the base principles of a sandwich/salad, chips, water, and perhaps a cookie or pickle remained. The food was tasty and I tried a litany of options.</p>

<p>Every day after lunch we had a speaker in the auditorium. The speakers were from a variety of backgrounds and perspectives, but they were all interesting and cool. We had a tour of Draper, which was awesome. The Draper CEO came in to speak, and afterwards called a few people and me up to give us internship offers. I was excited, and we took pictures together.</p>

<p>On the weekends we would meet as a class sometimes. We met up together for the MIT SwapFest. I biked for 1.5 hours each way from my house, which was super fun. I got a ladybug drone from the SwapFest.</p>

<p>After class I would hang out with my friends on campus at RSI. Sometimes I’d visit them at their makerspaces (metropolis!) or just at the student center, and we’d have fun together, brainstorming and learning lockpicking and having fun.</p>

<p>The day before the final day, we stayed after to help set up the arena. We had a pizza party, and then I visited the caving club to learn to tie knots in a stairwell.</p>

<p>On the final day (Saturday), we went upstairs to the embsec presentation area. I had been informed just hours before that beyond my normal group presentation, I was also presenting an exploit with a friend during our “camera time”. I made slides and practiced hurriedly, but the presentation went well during the canera time itself.</p>

<p>I felt that it was really echo-y, but the camera’s mic was good and didn’t pick up any of the echo. i was pleasantly surprised during the camera time when the lead instructor began giving out trophies/awards. I was given a cute among us statue with Confidentiality, Integrity, and Authenticity written on it, as well as the letters MVP. They declared it was an overall award for the best “among us”, which I found hilarious.</p>

<p>We went down to have lunch from the food trucks after, and while the lines were long, a group let me go before them to demonstrate how to order (and because they were remote, and their friend was my groupmate). The food was delicious, with fried chicken bits and ice cream and chips. I met some friends from my school and an old brother of one of them, who was previously an instructor for embsec.</p>

<p>Afterwards all of embsec met up outside, and undering the scorching sun we gave farewell speeches. When I went home on the T with a friend from the course, I saw friends from my school. It was a nice send off, and though I left BWSI on the red line, I’ll carry the memories and what I learned with me.</p>]]></content><author><name>stephanie</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last month, I attended Beaver Works Summer Institute (BWSI). BWSI is a summer engineering program for high schoolers, with both online and in-person options and a variety of different course options, from unmanned aerial vehicles to e-textiles. I took the Embedded Security and Hardware Hacking course, a class in-person at MIT over the span of a month. It was absolutely amazing.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/06/03/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post" /><published>2024-06-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-06-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/06/03/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/06/03/first-post.html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my blog :)</p>

<p>This is the first post. I’ll update more soon, but you can find my old posts at <a href="https://swan07.vercel.app/">my old website</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>stephanie</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to my blog :)]]></summary></entry></feed>